[♪ opening theme song playing]
DAEMONS OF THE SHADOW REALM
[birds chirping]
[ASAGIRI] They found us.
But we know the way
to enter Tadera's hideout now.
So we may recover the remains
of those who once served us,
the ones who went missing.
That will suffice, Asagiri.
BIG BROTHER AND LITTLE BROTHER
[YURU] I noticed something when
I was running around earlier.
Their attacks were relentless.
Except for when
I hid behind this spot.
♪
They're here.
Tenaga-Ashinaga's master.
Come on out.
[BOY] But are you gonna
kill me if I do?
[gasps] That's a young voice.
Is it a kid?
[YURU] Your fate depends
on what you say.
[WOMAN] No mercy.
Hard to believe he's a kid, too.
[rustling]
[whimpering softly]
I'll answer
any question you have!
Please, just spare my life!
I don't wanna die!
You've gotta be joking.
This brat's
barely out of diapers!
Are you Tenaga-Ashinaga's
master?
Yes, I am.
Or I guess, I was.
What are you doing here, kiddo?
You got a name?
I'm sorry to intrude.
I'm Ken Tadera.
I believe...
-my father owns this house?
-[ALL] Uh?
[YURU] Mmm?
Run that one by me again.
[YURU] You said your dad?
So this is your son, Dera?
No, no, slow down, buddy!
There's no way I...
[Dera grunts softly]
I don't know this kid!
That pause was awful pregnant.
Your mother!
Is she from Japan?
We're both from Ethiopia!
And what's her name?
It's Abeba Tesfaye!
Yep! I 100% haven't heard
that name before!
This kid isn't mine!
Sorry, but are you Ryu Tadera,
by any chance?
Dad told me
some stories about you.
I'm Ken Tadera,
the son of Roei.
It's nice to meet you.
[Dera gasps softly]
Wait, Roei?
I feel like I know that name
from a while back.
[DERA]
That's my predecessor's name.
And also my pop's.
It makes sense
you'd remember him.
He did my job
when you were a kid.
So, you've met him.
Wait, we have the same father?
How old are you?
I'm 13.
So we're 22 years apart?
How nice to see
long-lost half-brothers
find each other!
'Tis a moving chance reunion!
Hey, that's great, Dera!
Your family's gotten bigger!
I'm sorry, am I supposed
to find this heartwarming?
So, listen,
I accidentally overheard
some of your conversation
from before.
This guy with the blonde hair...
Didn't you say he's one of the
twins from Higashi Village?
So he must be
Mine and Nagisa's son.
-[YURU] Uh?
-[KEN] Dad told me about them.
Hold on. Are you saying
you know my mom and dad?
I don't think I'd go that far.
But they needed someone
to teach them
how to escape
Higashi's barrier,
and my dad agreed to help.
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
My old man did what now?
He never told me that!
You're serious?
You've got one chance!
If you know
where my parents are,
-then tell me!
-[Ken screams]
Please don't kill me! [cries]
[WOMAN] Rough for you.
The twin's parents ran away
from Higashi Village
and joined the Kagemoris.
If your dad helped them,
kinda makes it seem like
the Taderas are working
-as Kagemori spies.
-[Dera exclaims]
You're right.
Uh, I should explain some more.
[WOMAN] Nope, not another word
out of you!
I've already heard
too much stuff
I got no business knowing!
Look, you lot saved my life.
So I'll return the favor
by keeping my mouth shut!
Asuma won't be hearing
about this kid.
And I'm not gonna
try to sell this info
as a tip to Higashi Village,
either!
Much appreciated.
[WOMAN] With that said,
you gonna kill me,
or can I leave now?
[Dera sighs] Asuma's daemon
did manage to track us here.
So the route's
already out there,
and this place is
all but useless to me.
That means offing you now
isn't gonna do me any good.
So I don't care.
What do you think, Yuru?
Why ask me?
[DERA] This old bag...
[clears throat]
This lady, she tried
to rat you out
to Tenaga-Ashinaga
during the fight.
[YURU] Oh, that? It's fine.
I didn't feel like
she wanted to kill us.
[WOMAN]
The kid's only got beef
with people who actively
want him dead?
That's shortsighted.
Is your husband
in this line of work?
Nah. Tried to settle down
with an ordinary civil servant.
He doesn't know
the stuff I do on the side,
and I don't want him to.
Well, I think it's safe
to let her walk away.
I'm cool with it
as long as you are.
[woman sighs]
[WOMAN]
What upstanding gentlemen.
Poor guys.
Always wondered what happened
to the Kagemori agents
who went missing after being
sent to tail a Tadera.
I know that's not
how I'd wanna go.
Before I leave,
would you mind
letting me bury the guys
who came with me so they're
not just lying out here?
I mean, they got no family
to hold a funeral for them.
Sure, have at it.
Just put 'em wherever you want.
I'll help you.
You were talking about
killing me so casually.
Now you're gonna help
your enemy bury the dead?
I gotta say, kid, your ethics
are all over the place.
You always need
to bury the dead.
Otherwise, you risk a plague.
Something like that
can wipe out a village
in the blink of an eye.
[WOMAN]
Oh. So that's how he lived.
[YURU] Besides,
the sooner you're gone,
the sooner we can talk to Ken.
Hey, Left and Right,
mind lending a hand?
[Right grunting]
-[woman stammers]
-[Right chuckles]
So does this look deep enough
for your needs?
Oh, I didn't mean
"a hand" literally.
But whatever works.
[Ken exhales softly]
So, uh...
-Brother--
-[DERA] Call me Ryu.
[KEN] All right.
Then, Mr. Ryu...
Thanks for beating those
scary daemons for me.
You really saved my butt there.
[Dera exhales softly]
[YURU] Oh, yeah.
I know you can form
a contract with a daemon
using your own blood.
But what happens
if you want out?
Is there a peaceful way
you can dissolve
an unwanted contract?
The contract's void
as long as all parties agree.
Then everything goes back
to the way it was.
[YURU] So they talk it out?
Uh-huh. The master-servant thing
is for convenience.
In reality, we're all equal.
[BUNBUN] We've got feelings
of our own, mister.
I get it.
And in that case...
Is it the same for us?
Indeed.
If you so desired,
we would return to being statues
at Higashi Village's entrance.
And though our current contract
isn't completely
without limitations,
I will admit we're happy being
able to move about.
We would rather stay like this.
'Twas four hundred years.
There is much yet to see
in this new world
before returning to our post.
-[RIGHT] Listen, child.
-[Ken yelps]
Not all daemons you will meet
are as kind-hearted as us,
nor half so amenable to reason.
To carelessly free
strange daemons
is to invite your own doom.
[KEN] I know I messed up!
[whimpers]
Huh. I recall you said the power
of Seal is dangerous.
But reflect now
on moments like these,
where you could seal
a wicked daemon
without any contract!
Should Break be used instead,
it would create a stray daemon.
But Seal merely
locks them away
into their relic,
safe and sound.
In some ways, it's a kindness.
[woman gasps]
[WOMAN] Back just like that.
[DERA] Feels like you
never even left, yeah?
You good to make it home?
[WOMAN] Yeah, sure.
[DERA] Oh...
Give Asuma my love,
won't you?
From the heart.
[door closes]
[bird cawing]
[woman sighs]
[WOMAN]
I think I'm ready to retire.
[DERA] With her gone...
You're up, Ken.
Why don't you go ahead
and give us any info you got?
First, I wanna make it clear
I have no idea
where Yuru's parents are
at all.
[Yuru groans softly]
[KEN] I wish I did,
but I don't even know
where my own dad is,
let alone his.
No kidding.
Wonder if the old man's
kicked the bucket.
Huh? I was kinda
hoping you would know
something about
where I could find him.
Sorry, buddy.
Didn't you call him
your predecessor earlier?
I figured he was already dead
if you were
referring to him like that.
[DERA] Don't go puttin' words
in my mouth.
While we're at it,
I said this is a Tadera daemon,
but it's not mine.
Its contract is
with my predecessor.
Maybe he meant to give it to me,
but he dipped first.
[YURU] Ah. That's why
it didn't try to help you
when you were in danger.
Seemed strange,
since I've always seen daemons
try to protect their masters.
A few years ago,
Dad taught me all sorts of stuff
about daemons.
He said it was important
to know, just in case.
It was tough,
since he'd only come visit us
every once in a while.
[DERA] Mm-hmm.
[KEN] Then he'd leave again,
sometimes without saying a word.
That's him.
[KEN] My mom died the other day.
I tried to reach out,
but I couldn't get him.
I was all alone.
I thought I had to get stronger
so I could survive on my own.
So I decided to contract
a couple powerful daemons.
I found where Tenaga-Ashinaga
were sealed
and offered them my blood,
but they wound up
being really evil.
At first,
I thought it would be fine,
since as their master,
they wouldn't be
able to hurt me.
But no matter what I said,
they wouldn't listen.
I freed them,
so I knew I had to do something
to stop them
from running rampant.
And knowing the path
to the Lost House,
you decided to trap them inside.
[KEN] Right. Dad taught me
about this place a while back.
Always wondered
why he passed this job to me
ten years ago
almost out of nowhere.
It was around the same time
Yuru's parents
fled from the village.
One day, he tells me
I have to manage
all of our work going forward,
and then he's out the door.
That was the last
I heard from him.
And now it all makes sense.
Bastard dumped
the responsibilities on me.
Split before anything
incriminating came his way.
Didn't realize he had
some rugrat in another country.
[Ken gasps]
I guess he wanted
to keep us out of his work,
because he didn't talk
much about it.
Sometimes he'd drink,
and a complaint
or two would slip out.
Miss Nagisa wasn't
from the village, right?
Since she was from down here,
she was able to tell
my dad was the same.
She dug into Dad's past to
find his dirty little secrets.
Then threatened to tell everyone
if he didn't teach her
the way out.
He told me if I met her,
I shouldn't trust
her kind appearance.
She's a tigress
in sheep's clothing.
[Yuru gasps]
[YURU] Not bad, Mom.
That wasn't all he said.
He pretty openly despised
Higashi Village's traditions
involving the twins.
But in this case,
all he did was teach them
how to leave.
He didn't help them
actually escape.
Still, that meant he defied
the will of Higashi Village.
And he had been feuding
with the Kagemoris
for so long at that point,
he had nowhere to go.
Maybe retiring
was his only option.
[doorbell chimes]
DANNO
-[DERA] Sweetie, we're home.
-Is Yuru here?
Are you okay?
What happened to your face?
Oh, uh... It's fine.
Just a scratch.
Sorry I didn't tell you
when I left.
[HANA] Oh, you had me
worried sick, young man!
But you're all right.
I'm so relieved!
[YURU] I can't believe
Hana actually got this worried
about me.
She's truly kind.
[HANA] I am so glad
we're not gonna be wracked
with medical bills!
[Dera grunts]
[HANA] Amazed
you're in one piece, Dera.
Kinda lucky
after picking a fight
with the Kagemoris like that.
Oh, where to begin.
Ah, I'll explain it all later.
HORSE BETTING TICKET
-Let me crash for a few minutes.
-[rustling]
Uh?
[HANA] Gambling?
Fooling around?
[Dera stammers]
[KEN] Hello, nice to meet you.
My name is Ken Tadera.
Thank you for welcoming me
into your home.
Tadera?
A love child?
Off the top of your head,
what's the value of your assets?
Oh, no! Calculating
the divorce settlement already?
I'm dead broke,
and my only assets are
some land and a house.
Sadly, both of those
are Tadera clan daemons,
so you won't get them
if we split up!
[HANA] Daemons you have
to pay property taxes on?
DAEMONS OF THE SHADOW REALM
[HANA] Hi everyone!
My name is Hana Danno!
I work as a retainer
and runner for Higashi Village.
I live down the mountain
with my cute little fur babies!
But things took
a turn for the worse!
Dera, my kinda boss,
strongarmed me
into marrying him!
[Dera laughs]
[HANA] But my heart will always
belong to you, Jason Statham!
What's more, he's helping
a kid with serious baggage!
Plus there's his own.
The gambling! The infidelity!
The worthless real estate!
And worst of all...
His secret love child!
Every day's another
exciting development
in the life of the beautiful,
young newlywed Hana Danno.
I've been trying to tell you,
the kid doesn't belong to me.
[HANA] Okay, let's sum it up.
You used Left and Right
to try and find your parents,
but thought you saw your sister,
and got dragged off
to Kagemori manor
to reunite with her for real.
Then, you helped them deal
with a third-party
kidnapping attempt.
And the Kagemori clan head
provided breakfast.
And on the way home,
you gambled, womanized,
and picked up your love child.
[DERA] Those last two
weren't true. I swear!
But I'm not hearing you
deny you went gambling.
[DERA] I will not.
The previous clan head
never bothered
to tell me the kid existed.
He's not my secret love child.
[YURU] Your father cheated?
Don't just ask that, Yuru.
[DERA] The old man
and my ma called it quits
way before Ken here was born.
The kid's mom was
probably his legal wife.
Not like any of us have a right
to judge him for it, anyway.
[YURU] On that note...
I think our family should
take Ken in for a little while.
Oh, you would!
[DERA] Come on, he's got
nowhere else to go!
Don't you feel sorry for him?
[HANA] I do not,
and will never, like kids!
Don't add another one
like it's no big deal!
I've been told that many hands
make light work.
And all children are a treasure.
Well, I love Japan's
declining birthrate!
And don't break
child labor laws!
Plus, we barely know this kid.
How can we trust
he's not a spy from our enemies?
He's safe for sure.
I don't detect
a shred of bloodlust.
-[Kotetsu meows]
-[Hana sighs]
[HANA] Time for a quick lesson.
You can't just judge people
off of vibes alone.
For example...
[YURU] Mm?
[Yuru grunting]
[HANA] Consider me, now.
There's no part of me
that wants to kill you.
But what would you do
if I changed my mind?
Too late to escape
-at this point.
-[Yuru chokes]
Hey, honey?
Please, no domestic violence.
[HANA] 'Kay.
[Ken trembling]
[DERA] That was a good lesson!
You just learned
Hana's the scariest person
in this house
when she gets angry.
And that's my wife!
You've known that all along,
and still every day
you choose to poke the bear.
[KEN] You guys are way scarier
than I was expecting.
Is everyone
with the village like this?
[HANA] Maybe
I shouldn't be saying this,
but no normal person
would be caught dead
associating
with Higashi Village.
[Ken gasps]
Even if the pup
is after our heads,
he would pose us nary a threat.
Our numbers should
prove insurmountable
for someone his age.
Well, yeah. I suppose.
Anyway...
My mom fixed this up for me
before she passed away.
Please, use it to help cover
living expenses.
[HANA] A bank book?
[YURU] Bank book?
[DERA] Think a ledger
for keeping track of your gold.
Sort of.
[Hana groans] It hasn't been
updated in years,
so we don't know
what the actual balance is.
Here, Dera. Take care of it.
On it!
Go ahead and pick up dinner
while you're out!
[DERA] Yes, ma'am!
[YURU] Watching her
boss around her boss
feels like watching
a mouse eat a snake.
[door opens]
-[DERA] I'm back.
-[door closes]
Hey, honey?
I think you're gonna agree
we should look after Ken
for a little while.
What?
[Hana gasps]
[HANA] Ken, sweetie,
are you a citizen here?
Of course. I've been registered
for a while now, thankfully.
[HANA]
Then on behalf of all of us,
I'd like to welcome you
to our family!
Thank you so much! [cries]
[Hana grunts]
[HANA]
Why is this kid so loaded?
A child does not need
this much money!
[DERA] I agree
the balance is crazy, but look.
There are monthly deposits here.
He's paying child support.
A man of principles!
You should be so proud!
What a stand-up guy!
[DERA] Like hell he is!
I gotta remind you
what he left me with?
Check it.
This last deposit
is pretty recent.
Good news for you.
Means he's still alive
and kickin'.
-That's awesome!
-Then we should go look for him!
All right, but where to start?
Hey, Ken, do you have
any photos of him?
Mm, no, he'd never
let me take any.
He was a private man.
Yeah, I'm aware.
I'm in the exact same boat.
Don't have anything
showing his face.
Who are we supposed to ask
if we don't even have
a picture to show?
Seeing how you operate,
I'm sure he has
a million aliases.
We could try to find
someone who knew him
through Ken's mother.
Sorry. Before she passed,
my mom worked at a bar
in Katsushika, Tokyo.
I already tried.
I talked to every one
of her friends from her job.
Asked them if they knew
where my dad was,
and I got the same reply.
Gonna go out on a limb here
and say no one knew a thing?
-[KEN] Yeah.
-[Dera sighs]
[DERA] No wonder the Kagemoris
couldn't catch him
if his two sons can't manage.
Eh, it's fine.
We'll have to ask
the Higashi Village folks
and see if we can get any
roundabout leads through them.
Not my bake sale,
not my brownies.
You wanna do that,
you can handle it alone.
Yeah, yeah, I know.
You kids let the grownups
handle the details.
Time to eat your dinner.
And wash that grime off
before you go to bed!
-[KEN] Okay.
-[YURU] Okay.
[Yuru exclaims]
How can they afford
to let me use this much water
all by myself?
I feel like I'm doing
something wrong!
GREW UP IN THE MOUNTAINS,
WHERE WATER IS PRECIOUS
[KEN] Yuru?
Are you all right
sleeping on that flat futon?
Bedding down here's too soft
compared to what I'm used to.
If you're sure, I feel bad
for taking the better futon
when I'm nothing
but a freeloader in your house.
You're part of Dera's clan,
so you're basically family
as far as I'm concerned.
-Make yourself at home, Ken.
-Okay.
For what it's worth,
I hope we find your dad
before long.
Me too.
He might not know...
about my mom's passing,
I mean.
[YURU] Hm.
[Ken cries softly]
[YURU] Hm?
And for whatever
it's worth, Yuru...
I hope we find
your parents, too.
[continues crying]
♪
[door opens]
[door closes]
What's in the vase?
Ken's mom's remains, apparently.
He hasn't found a good spot
to lay her to rest.
Man, that's gotta be rough.
[Dera gulping]
-[Jiro whines]
-[Kotetsu meows]
[HANA] Well, we should check
with Ken in the morning.
If he wants, we could make
a grave for her on my mountain.
In character.
Little miss Gravedigger.
[HANA] Just tell me
when it's your turn.
I'll put you six feet under.
-[Dera chuckles]
-[door opens]
-[HANA] Good night, Dera.
-[door closes]
[Dera sighs]
[DERA] Good night.
[♪ closing theme song playing]
NEXT EPISODE PREVIEW
[ASA] I'm glad I got to hear
your voice.
[JIN] There actually
are faint lines visible here.
It wasn't made
by a simple razor.
[ASUMA] Uncle! Hello.
EPISODE 12
RETAINER AND SHAMAN